Daniel Barranco

Full Stack Web Developer

Atlanta, GA

danielbarranco@gmail.com, <u>www.danielbarranco.com</u>, 404.218.6088 https://github.com/carrottop17

Summary

Experienced entrepreneur capable of creating dynamic and creative apps and websites. Familiar with JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Python, MongoDB, Express, Apache, Linux and MySOL

Projects

Ecommerce App

http://www.danielbarranco.com/imagecomics/#/

Ecommerce site: Node.js, Express, MongoDB and AngualrJS (MEAN stack) I created an ecommerce site where you can order Image comics, pay for them with a credit card and have them shipped to you. The front-end is built with AngularJS, HTML and CSS. The back-end is an api driven by Express and MongoDB in Node.js. Users can register an account, login and add their comics to the shopping cart. They can then checkout and it will add their order and information to the MongoDB. I encountered a problem removing items from the cart once the user had already added. I then figured out how to split the cookie string, loop through it, splice out the deleted title, rejoin the string and put the new cart back in the cookies.

Hillary vs Trump Tweets

http://danielbarranco.com/angular-tweets/

App to compare tweets: Twitter API, JavaScript, AngularJS

I used AngularJS to create a Single Page App to compare tweets about Hillary and Trump. I used Angular Material to handle the modal and created a custom directive for use with the menu.

Pictionary

http://www.danielbarranco.com/chat-room/

Multiplayer drawing game: Node.js, Socket.io

Started out making a chatroom app and finally created a drawing game that uses Socket.io to allow players to draw on the same canvas while using different computers. I encountered a problem with the canvas stretching but solved it using absolute

positioning and inline dimensions for the canvas.

Revelry

http://shirletterly.com/hacker-snackers/#/

Music Festival search app: Google Maps API, Ticketmaster API, JavasScript, AngularJS I worked on this project with a team of three in which I was the SCRUM master. We created a website that searches the US for music festivals based on several search criteria. There are still some bugs with the search feature that I am correcting. We utilized SCRUM and agile methodology to complete the MVP in a week.

Work Experience

Barranco Beverage, Inc. - CFO / Partner

2003 - 2016

- Founded and ran a beverage installation and distribution company with annual sales exceeding \$1.8 million. A family business with 12 -15 employees.
- Headed up all marketing, accounting, IT, logistics and inventory management.
- Created and trademarked the brand Frosty Fruit, a 100% fruit juice slushy product sold in over 600 schools around the US.
- Wrote RFPs and landed contracts with Cobb, Gwinnett and Fulton Counties. Along with companies such as RaceTrac, Pepsi, Walmart and Target.
- GA distributor for national brands including Cornelius, Bunn and Cooltropics.

Richmond American Homes - National Internet Marketing Manager

2001 - 2003

- Designed the Web site and facilitated XML data feeds to selected vendor websites.
- Served as Project Manager for all projects pertaining to company Web site.
- Developed and supported marketing information on the company Intranet.
- Optimized search engine results via pay-per-click advertising and doorway pages.
- Developed new processes and training programs for new Internet marketing programs.
- Coordinated e-mail and direct mail campaigns for 17 divisions.

Generation21 Learning Systems - Webmaster / Marketing Coordinator 2000 – 2001

- Improved search engine rankings by over 80 percent.
- Established and enforced procedures for updating the Web site.
- Encouraged, managed, and facilitated weekly updates to the site to ensure repeat visits.
- Wrote and updated internal training courses about Generation21's Web site.
- Tracked monthly direct mail campaigns of over 40,000 pieces using the Onyx database.
- Customized mailing lists for monthly promotional efforts.

Education

DigitalCrafts

2016 - Present

16 week immersive development bootcamp. Developing front-end web applications using HTML, CSS, Javascript and multiple JavaScript libraries and frameworks. Developing full-stack web applications using the MEAN (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, Node.js) stack and LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, Python) stack.

University of Colorado at Boulder

1995 - 1999

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration. Emphasis in Marketing and Operational Management.